<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Xiurou Wu</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Xiurou Wu</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Xiurou Wu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Spatial Model of Multi-destination Trips: An application to commercial fishing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/wps/multidestination/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/wps/multidestination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-examples-of-multi-destination-trips-subfigure-a-from-ofarrell-et-al-2019httpswwwnaturecomarticless41467-019-11106-y-subfigure-b-from-albers-et-al-2020httpswwwtandfonlinecomdoifull1010801742177220191692143-and-subfigure-c-from-parsons-et-al-2021httpswwwjournalsuchicagoedudoi101086710714&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/multidestination.png&#34; alt=&#34;LocationChoice&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Examples of multi-destination trips, Subfigure (a) from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41467-019-11106-y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;O&amp;rsquo;Farrell et al. 2019&lt;/a&gt;, Subfigure (b) from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/17421772.2019.1692143&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Albers et al. 2020&lt;/a&gt;, and Subfigure (c) from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.journals.uchicago.edu/doi/10.1086/710714&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Parsons et al. 2021&lt;/a&gt;.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;Coauthors&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesnsanchirico.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;James N. Sanchirico&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High-resolution spatial-temporal mobility data are generating new insights into human behavior. Motivated by these insights, we construct a novel model of a multidestination trip that incorporates simultaneous discrete and continuous decisions on extensive and intensive margins, including location choice, time and effort allocation at each site, travel route, and trip length. While we apply the model to commercial fishing, multidestination trips are present, for example, in recreation and tourism, natural resource hunting and gathering (e.g., timber, fuel woods), and transportation planning.  In the fishing literature, the prior research on fishing trips focuses on choosing discrete fishing locations, treating all other trip decision margins as exogenous. We show analytically that all decisions are interconnected and conditional on the underlying vessel capital. Applying state-of-the-art numerical methods for mixed integer optimization, we compare the spatial patterns of a forward-looking vessel to a myopic vessel that essentially represents the behavioral model underpinning the large discrete choice literature in fishery and recreational demand on site choices. We find that vessel heterogeneity leads to different spatial patterns of resource use, including sites fished, effort allocations, and trip lengths. We demonstrate the policy usefulness of the model by considering the distributional impacts of a fuel tax or removal of a fuel subsidy. The existence of high-resolution data in environmental and natural resource economics opens up the possibility of a unifying framework of resource use, such as the one developed here, as differences in spatial and temporal data availability that led to methodological divergences become homogenized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: natural resource economics, recreation demand, mixed-integer programming, capacity utilization, random utility model&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Manuscript available by request&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Ecosystem Service Conflicts in China’s Lake Poyang</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/wps/lakepoyang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/wps/lakepoyang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-siberian-cranes-wintering-in-lake-poyang-photo-by-haiyan-zhou&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/cranes.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;Lake Poyang&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Siberian Cranes wintering in Lake Poyang, photo by Haiyan Zhou
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;Coauthors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://are.ucdavis.edu/people/faculty/emeriti/james-wilen/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;James E. Wilen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesnsanchirico.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;James N. Sanchirico&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper develops a model of ecosystem service management that illuminates the conflict between fishing operations and conservation of endangered and threatened waterfowl, specifically Siberian Cranes. The model is calibrated to fit the example of the China’s largest freshwater lake, Lake Poyang, the wintering ground for the last surviving population of Siberian Cranes. It captures important features of the lake&amp;rsquo;s hydrology, ecosystem, and economics to investigate the impact of uncoordinated and coordinated management of fishing and bird conservation.  The coordinated (joint) management problem is a three-state nonsmooth hybrid dynamic problem that is within-year continuous and between-year discrete. It is solved by the novel pseudo-spectral method from aerospace engineering. The current regulations do not account for the externality fishing imposes on the endangered cranes, which results in their population size decreasing over time. In general, we find prolonging the fishing season extends the cranes’ winter feeding and enhances survival but at a cost to the fishery. Then we examine compensation schemes for fishery communities that induce crane conservation. With the decline in natural landscape quality, importance grows for working landscapes to provide ecosystem services.The integrated framework I develop for coordinating institutions to maximize returns to ecosystem services in a working landscape applies directly to sustainable development, agricultural and otherwise, which competes for soil, water, and other natural resources in the same way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: bioeconomics, endangered species conservation, hybrid discrete-continuous model, pseudospectral method&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;research/lake_poyang_XW.pdf&#34;&gt;Manuscript&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crab management and marine heatwaves – the case of the red king crab management in Norway</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/ongoing/crab/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/ongoing/crab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-the-red-king-crab-was-an-unwanted-alien-species-for-a-long-time-before-it-became-a-bonanza-in-both-norway-and-russia-figure-red-king-crab-native-and-invasive-distributionhttpswwwgridanoresources7734&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/rkcdist.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;RKC&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      The red king crab was an unwanted alien species for a long time, before it became a bonanza in both Norway and Russia. (Figure: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.grida.no/resources/7734&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Red king crab native and invasive distribution&lt;/a&gt;])
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;Coauthors&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://snf.no/medarbeidere/margrethe-aanesen/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Margrethe Aanesen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This paper analyzes how marine heatwaves (MHWs) affect the red king crab (RKC) fisheries in Norway. Drawing insights from similar events in the northeast Pacific and the Bering Sea, we first employ a socio-ecological systems (SES) model to understand how changes in RKC productivity and distribution due to MHWs could impact local fishing communities and economic activities in northern Norway. Subsequently, we assess the effects of identified marine heatwaves on the utilization of fishing permits specific to coastal vessels capable of catching red king crabs, as well as on the associated landing activities. This study is particularly relevant because the RKC fishery, though based on an introduced species, has become economically significant for coastal communities in northern Norway, supporting both commercial fishing and tourism activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: marine heatwave, crab fisheries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research is part of my postdoctoral work, funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://snf.no/medarbeidere/sturla-f-kvamsdal/casino/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Winners and losers in the climate casino: Arctic marine resources under climate change (CASINO)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oceanic Drivers of Expected Losses from the Creation of Large Marine Protected Areas in the Eastern Tropical Pacific Ocean on Commercial Tuna Fleets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/ongoing/galapagos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/ongoing/galapagos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-marine-migratory-species-connectivity-in-the-eastern-tropical-pacific-ocean-migramar&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/etpospecies.png&#34; alt=&#34;Galapagos&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Marine migratory species connectivity in the Eastern Tropical Pacific ocean (Migramar).
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;Coauthors&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://jamesnsanchirico.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;James N. Sanchirico&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The paper provides an upper-bound estimate of the potential short-run catch loss in tuna fisheries from potential large-scale marine protected areas in the Eastern Tropical Pacific Ocean. We examine the hypothetical closures of the Galapagos EEZ of Ecuador and/or the Costa Rica Thermal Dome. Using a set level dataset of purse seine tuna fishing from 1996 to 2016, we  develop a method that decomposes the expected lost catch into two components: catch per set, number of sets in the potential area. This decomposition allows us to account for how protected areas and El Niño-Southern Oscillation (ENSO) regimes differently impact various aspects of the production process. Our findings reveal significant heterogeneity in the expected impacts across vessel classes and fishing flags. Smaller vessels from certain flags would face substantial impacts from closing the Galapagos EEZ, while others would be more affected by closing the Costa Rica Thermal Dome. Additionally, we find that oceanographic conditions influence the magnitude of potential losses, with colder regimes leading to higher losses in the Galapagos EEZ and warmer regimes resulting in greater losses in the Costa Rica Thermal Dome. Our analysis contributes to the growing literature on large-scale ocean closures and provides a valuable tool for policymakers to better understand the distributional impacts of marine protected areas under varying oceanographic conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: marine protected areas, migratory species&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing identification strength of narrative sign restrictions for SVAR</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/ongoing/linearineq/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/ongoing/linearineq/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coauthors&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://gafarov.ucdavis.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Bulat Gafarov&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sign restrictions provide a range of models that most economists agree upon.
In the recent years, additional proposals has been made including restrictions in dynamic factor models, narrative sign and ranking restrictions that can provide large and growing number of identifying inequalities resulting in point identification.
In this paper, we provide testable necessary and sufficient conditions under which these bounds collapse to single point.
The main necessary condition is positive linear dependence of the vectors of sign-restricted IRF coefficients.
We provide a simple test for this condition with standard chi-squared critical values that remain valid  in the presence of redundant sign-restrictions.
Our simulations suggest that the proposed test has high power against the alternative data generating process with partial-identification.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: SVAR, point identification, sign restrictions&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Value of Public Catch Information</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/ongoing/valueinfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/ongoing/valueinfo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-a-start-up-company-catchwise-visualizes-public-norwegian-catch-data-from-january-2023-this-screenshot-shows-a-heatmap-of-catch-and-catch-reports-photo-fiskeribladethttpswwwfiskeribladetno&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/catchwise.png&#34; alt=&#34;CASINO&#34; loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      A start up company, Catchwise, visualizes public Norwegian catch data from January 2023. This screenshot shows a heatmap of catch and catch reports. Photo: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fiskeribladet.no/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fiskeribladet&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Government monitoring and management collects private data that can become publicly accessible under transparent management. Meanwhile, technological advances have enabled novel sources of high-resolution mobility data that are inherently public. Together, these public data sources create opportunities for innovative digital platforms providing information services in the private sectors. This potential is exemplified in Norway&amp;rsquo;s fishing industry, where public access to fishing data has driven the development of digital platforms that aim for both sustainable fishing practices and energy efficiency.s driven the development of digital platforms that aim for both sustainable fishing practices and energy efficiency—critical objectives in the fishing industry&amp;rsquo;s efforts to adapt to and mitigate climate change. However, the value of information accessibility remains ambiguous, as better information may lead to increased fleet congestion in productive fishing grounds. Using natural experiments in Norwegian fisheries that altered the accessibility of public catch data, this paper analyzes how information availability affects fishing profit, fishing efficiency, and fleet congestion, focusing specifically on Norwegian bottom trawlers—the largest vessels in groundfish fisheries that face particular scrutiny for their carbon emissions and seabed impacts. This paper examines key sustainability metrics including bycatch rates, fuel consumption, carbon emissions, and seabed disturbance. This research provides insights into the trade-offs inherent in data transparency policies, particularly in the context of natural resource management where public sector data accessibility can drive private sector innovation while potentially affecting competitive dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;keywords&lt;/strong&gt;: value of information, congestion, climate change adaptation and mitigation, innovation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This research is part of my postdoctoral work, funded by &lt;a href=&#34;https://snf.no/medarbeidere/sturla-f-kvamsdal/casino/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Winners and losers in the climate casino: Arctic marine resources under climate change (CASINO)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Income Inequality and County Economic Resistance to Job Loss during the Great Recession</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/publication/journal-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/publication/journal-article/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
